## **Enrico Lucia**

#### **Australia**

15 unit, 500 Elizabeth Street Surry Hills, Sydney NSW 2010 Tel (AUS): +61 (0)478537512

Email: enrico.lucia.web@gmail.com

#### Italy

Via dei cinque archi 283, Velletri, RM 00049

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Develop efficient and intuitive user interfaces via Front end best practices for web applications while continuing to learn and expand my knowledge of emerging web technologies.

### **PROFILE**

A self-motivated professional with experience dominant experience in front end web development, plus marketing and design on high traffic websites including ryanair.com (largest low cost airline in Europe), healthdirect.gov.au (more than 200K visits per week), carergateway.gov.au, altroconsumo.it, cattolica.it, knowledgetoaction.co.uk and romaincampagna.it.

### **DEMONSTRATED STRENGTHS INCLUDE:**

- Working independently, efficiently and accurately within a large team of developers, designers, product managers and project managers utilizing Perforce to manage code, Jira to manage bug tracking and Rally to assist in the Agile software development methodology as well as Waterfall environment.
- Strong knowledge of web 2.0 best practices for Front End scripting, SEO, UX, Social Networking, Split A/B Interface Testing, Content Sharing, Asynchronous BackEnd/Frontend. RSS and JSON/JSONP.
- The ability to plan strategically and work through highly iterative design and UX journey phases while meeting strict deadlines within Agile Scrum Team methods.
- Proven ability to continually learn and grow within the field of web development, design and marketing. Most of my skills nowadays are self taught with the help of mentors, online resources and challenging projects within a professional environment.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# UX / UI Practice Lead and Manager – EME DIGITAL – MAR 2015– CURRENT emedigital.com.au / Sydney, Australia

A niche consulting company with strong focus on Adobe Marketing Cloud and Adobe Experience Manager. Aimed in the consulting industry to solve complex problems using the most effective technologies for the problem at hand. In my current role I have the opportunity to spread my expertise in Front End with web portals and content management systems such as Adobe CQ and Alfresco.

- Implementing and Integrating Alfresco ECMS solution.
- Development of Adobe AEM solutions to new and pre-existing e-commerce and web portals.

- Use of React / Redux / Flux / Aurelia / Angular / Task runner and manager / Nodejs on daily basis
- To be continued....

## Lead Front-End Web Developer – Ryanair Airline – JUL 2013– FEB 2015 ryanair.com / Dublin, Ireland

Ryanair is Europe's favourite low fares airline, operating more than 1,600 daily flights (over 500,000 per year) from 68 bases, across 1,600 low fare routes, connecting 186 destinations in 30 countries and operating a fleet of 300 new Boeing 737-800 aircraft. Ryanair has recently announced firm orders for a further 175 new Boeing aircraft, which will be delivered between 2014 and 2018. Ryanair currently has a team of more than 9,000 highly skilled professionals, will carry over 81.5 million passengers this year and has an outstanding 29-year safety record.

- Lead Front End Developer working on new version of ryanair.com.
- Wrote main core functionalities on front end that receive 15 million views per day.
- Developed front end implementation and usability of public REST APIs in Javascript / Backbone.js / Underscore.js / Require.js to get millions of queries per day.
- Developed front end implementation for real-time flight seach engine (skyscanner.com look alike) to get best fares on different filters.
- Developed Javascript modules; e.g. analytics plugin used to track user behavior, bookings, etc.
- Front End compatibilities debugging for tablets e.g. iOS tablets and Android tablets to ensure the most achevable user experience throughout the website.
- Developed and tested Ryanair corporate/investors website using Bootstrap best practices.
- Developed and tested Ryanair responsive newsletters in 14 different languages.
- Conducting and examining candidates interviews for Design and Development vacancy roles.
- Training and assisting new members of our Team in both Front End and Design.
- Mentoring all med/jr Front End developers throughout daily and long terms tasks.
- Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, Backbone.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Grunt, Yeoman, Bower, Handlbars, Less, Sass, Require.js, Bootstrap, iOS and Android debugging tools, JSPX, Tomcat, XML, RSS, Mercurial

## Senior Front-End Web Designer / Developer – Procom Group - OCT 2012 – JUN 2013 blendmedia.it / Roma, IT

Procom Group is a cross media agency in Rome IT operating with major Italian and International brands.

By working closely with experienced professionals from editory, web, tv and web tv I had the chance to enlarge my personal and professional prospective.

My major rule in this company was in most part undertaking and developing from scratch clients websites, where it was required a deep architectural study of the product as well as their competitors presence on the web.

- Develop from blueprints to the final for the final product for new and existing websites to engage as much as possible the final user.
- Mobile first approach and downscalable website architectures.
- Developing an maintaing Cattolica Assicurazioni http://www.cattolica.it/ web portal and affiliated product website, one of the most important Insurance Company in Europe, using Alfresco and hand-written Frontend MVC.
- Designed and developed Progettodivita.it, a web portal supported by a young community that operates nationally to provide services to the young generation of work force.
- Design and develop sites and email marketing assets for each client.
- Menthoring and assisting clients during the all process of the projects development.
- Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, Backbone.js, jQuery, PHP, HTML/CSS, JSPX, XML, RSS and Git
- Main platforms used while in this position include AlFresco, Magento, OsCommerce

## Senior Front-End Web Designer / Developer - VizionOnline ltd. - OCT 2011 - OCT 2012 viziononline.co.uk / London, UK

VizionOnline is a professional website design service London UK working with a number of leading brands.

As the most experienced member of the team I had a heavy influence on the running of the department. As such, I used my existing knowledge and experience to increase the efficiency of the team and improve the quality of their work.

Furthermore, as part of my commitment to learning I began to study User Experience Design which lead to me introducing a range of user-centred design techniques into the development process. This new focus on the experience of the end-users transformed the agency's output from quite standard websites for local businesses to high-traffic websites and ecommerce solutions.

- Build and maintain from psd to the final for the final result for new and existing websites to support new web 2.1 standards.
- As lead of a internation teamwork, I manage in maintaining/adding features requiring AJAX, DOM manipulation and API interaction. This includes website features such as a mobile optimisation, cross-browsable testing with multiple devices, SEO, user-friendly front end, eye-catching layout.
- Designed and developed Prelet.co.uk one of the most known and used website for Landlord furntiures impleted by using OpenCart and hand-written modules to support high-flow remote management with pre-compiled xls files.
- Design and develop sites and email marketing assets for each client.
- Create a modify existing modules for Wordpress, OpenCart and Joomla to client's specs
  according to the newest standards available at the moment achieved in most of the
  cases with PHP and Jquery.

- Helped launch a more outstanding corporate website for VizionOnline.
- My foremost contribution to the front-end team is to work client-side ideas and prespective management of the final produc to provide a practical pixel perfect UI based on the design team's specs. This is achieved mostly with HTML/CSS in a PHP framework. A strong understanding of javascript/jQuery and basic understanding of PHP is required to achieve success with this. In most of the cases I created UI mockups in Photoshop and provide them to the clients to help find a practical design solution that supports quality visual design, feature extensibility and code efficiency.
- My workflow includes managing my own team projects using Adobe Suite, IIS and Apache. For development workflow I use Dreamweaver/Coda, JSLint, firebug (firebug lite for IE), chrome devtools, jsfiddle, jQuery, jQueryUI, YSlow and W3C and CSS Validator.
- Main web technologies used while in this position include javascript, Backbone.js, Angular.js, jQuery, Grunt, PHP, HTML/CSS, JSPX, XML, RSS and Mercurial
- Main platforms used while in this position include OpenCart, Magento, Wordpress, OsCommerce

## Senior Front-End Web Designer / Developer - Teknoassist - SEP 2009 - OCT 2011 teknoassist.it/ Rome, IT

Teknoassist is a leading company providing web services particularly focused on lawyers. Lead for the Teknoassist corporate website and supervised a team of developers to assure consistency throughout all online channels.

Consulted on-site with clients for design and development of information kiosks. Developed training materials to be used by publishing experts in the development of italian law online materials. Assisted in the creation of company Web Standards and the mentoring of new employees. Developed Style Guides to streamline communications with cross-functional teams. Designed and deployed PHP/Javascript applications for divisional intranets to be used as educational tools.

- Assist in the planning process for all site marketing initiatives
- Design and develop site and email marketing assets
- Maintain the company's brand and strategy through all web channels
- Provide creative and content support for social networking and affiliate programs
- Migrated content to new platform for a major site-redesign
- Retrofitted all existing HTML/CSS to validate
- Create and mantain a well-structured data-entry platform for a national well-known law consultancy company in Italy
- Implemented SEO on all static web content
- Won company award "Sito web dell'anno 2011 Categoria: Confronto" ('Website of the Year 2011 – Category: Compare') <a href="www.altroconsumo.it">www.altroconsumo.it</a>, entirely developed and designed by the internal team.

- Create and implement a hand-written Corporate CMS
- Most work was accomplished using Adobe CS5,Coda,Dreamweaver, firebug,W3C and CSS Validator
- Conducting competitor analysis on competitors websites to identify the strengths and weaknesses of alternative solutions or new approaches.
- Main web technologies used while in this position include VanillaJS, AJAX, JSON, ¡Query, PHP, HTML/CSS
- Main platforms used while in this position include OpenCart, Wordpress

## Web Developer – Dexma srl - JUN 2006 – AUG 2009 dexma.it / Rome, IT

I was employed on a Full Time basis as a Web Developer. During this stage of my career I matured a successful vision of what the key points are to deliver a valuable and usable website thanks to my experienced colleagues whom introduced me first on the best trends in web development and then to consolidate my professional knowledge. At Dexma I have mostly worked on the following activities.

- Marketing researches on competitors and users tendencies online.
- Improving and creating implementations of both back and front end on existing websites and associated products such as cms and newsletters.
- Testing, debugging websites and related products.
- Programming according to latest trends and standard guidelines meeting.
- Producing maintainable documentation and dev-ops guidelines.
- Provided IT support.
- My main projects at Dexma is Romaincampagna.it (financed by the Tourism Organization of Rome) in developing the front-end applications of the whole platform.
- Retrofitted all existing HTML/CSS to validate.
- Main platforms used while in this position include Joomla, Zencart, MailChimp.

### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATION**

#### 2006

Diploma as Accountant and Bookkeeper, Business High School

#### 2005

**Expert in electronics and security systems**, Professional Institute Albaform

### 2007

Adobe® Photoshop® CS4 ACE Certified

### OTHERS SKILLS AND QUALIFICATION

**Excellent IT skills:** Microsoft Packages, Open Office, Internet, Outlook, Database Systems including Prestege, Google applications

**Masterful in Programming languages:** VanillaJS, nodejs, require.js, angular.js, backbone.js, jquery, json, html, xml, xhtml and css, social networks api.

Masterful in Operation systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac Os x, Linux.

Version control systems: Git, Mercurial, SVN.

Masterful in CMS: Wordpress, Joomla, Joomla (Virtuemart), ZenCart, Opencart, Magento.

Excellent Kwnoledge working: mysgl, sgl, c++, flash, social media marketing, seo.

**Hand coding CSS/HTML**: Compatible with IE8, IE\* and standards compliant browsers, optimization for portable devices.

**Adobe Creative Suite:** Expert level. Smart use of colour combination and disposition on websites. Always searching for creative inspirations.

Other work experiences 2004/2006: Computer technician, sale representative, web producer

Driving: Full Clean Driving Licence (EU) held since 2005, Full Clean Driving Licence (AUS) held since 2015,

Languages: Italian - native, English- fluent, Spanish - intermediate

### **SAMPLES**

http://www.ukwda.com - UK Web Design Association member

http://github.com/enricolucia - Github

http://enricolucia.com - Personal Website

http://www.html.it - I collaborate on an italian online magazine for professional Web designers and developers on voluntary basis

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request